hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
given two blue squares and it wants to
know what is the area of the red
triangle and I'm noticing something it's
not giving us anything about the
distance between the two squares so it
could realistically be any one of these
scenarios so I'm guessing every single
one of these red triangles have the
exact same area if you want to try it on
your own pause it right now because I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 so first
let's look at the formula for the area
of a triangle area equals 12 base time
height looking at this triangle we don't
know the base so let's call it X and
then for the height of this triangle we
need something at right angles this
right here would be at right angles
because this is a square so this is also
right angles this right here will be the
height of our triangle we don't know
that either so let's call it y so now
let's update this formula the base of
our triangle's X so let's call this x
and the height of our triangle is y so
let's call this y so this is what we're
trying to figure out so next let's use
the areas of the blue squares if this
one has an area of 16 each side will be
equal to four and if this one has an
area of 36 each side will be equal to
six and then from here just like this
was a right angle right here this one
would also be a right angle and then if
we look at this angle right here let's
call it Theta this angle will also be
Theta because these are vertical angles
and vertical angles are always congruent
so let's take this whole thing and copy
it down here and I want to focus on
these white triangles Let's Line them up
like this these are similar right
triangles we know that because because
they have two pairs of congruent angles
so that means we can set up a proportion
we can say the base of this triangle 4
over the base of this triangle X is
equal to the height of this triangle y
ided by the height of this triangle 6
and from here we can cross multiply x *
Y is equal to XY and on the other side 4
* 6 is equal to 24 and now we have x * y
that's all we really needed up here so
we can scoot this up here and in the
place of x y let's plug in 24 1 12 * 24
is equal to 12 and let's give it a label
of me squared this is the answer to our
question the area of the red triangle is
12 M squar and that'll be true for all
of these red triangles they all have an
area of 12 M squar how exciting now I'm
trying to put together an end card
here's a button to subscribe and here's
a nice video you can check out how
exciting